<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>getdilip.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A page to express thoughts, share ideas and finally a transformation from Agyani to A Gyani!</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>My First job experience :)</title>
	  <link>//my-first-job-experience</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-05-16T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//my-first-job-experience</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>What happens when you don’t understand the things taught by a teacher in the class? You ask your friend to explain and then the miracle happens, the equations which were taught by a highly qualified professional didn’t get into your head but you completely grasp the whole scenario when taught by a person just like you!</p>

<p>This is not the miracle of your friend but the miracle of personalized learning. This is what university students as home tutors provide. Thus, it makes an individual learn better and grow better. Its a very helping tradition, for all the three members, the child, the tutor, and parents. The practice should be encouraged in for a better and interconnected educational society.</p>

<p>I started giving tuitions at my residence to some school going students during the four years of my engineering course. I chose the time slot of 6:30 AM to 9:30 AM and reserved the evenings for my own studies.</p>

<p>It started with just two students and soon reached 30, split into multiple batches. This was the best way where I was revising the stuff I read before, my aptitude and IQ were automatically being revised and polished, in fact, I was indirectly preparing for job interviews. Meanwhile, the fees I got was more than enough as a pocket money. I became financially independent to the most extent and was able to support my expenses including the college fees and books.</p>

<p>It helped me improve not just my IQ and aptitude but also in many other areas like- public speaking, group discussions, soft skills, self-confidence and problem-solving while exchanging questions and answers. And above all was the respect I get from my students as well as their parents. These whole things made me a job ready and guess what it also helped me ace the very first campus placement.</p>

<p><strong>I don’t mention this (“my first job experience”) on my resume but whenever I see my students doing good in their life makes me happy and proud. This was an excellent experience which taught me more than just any other job could do. Peace!</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Virtual Resource pool</title>
	  <link>//the-virtual-resource-pool</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2017-11-24T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-virtual-resource-pool</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I have seen few HR people on LinkedIn discussing the poor joining ratios and asking why some candidates don’t pick up their calls after the interview schedules.</p>

<p>I have a similar question to them from a candidate’s point of view, why do some companies hire candidates and never send them the offer letter?</p>

<p>Two years back I had to travel ~30 km for the Accenture interview. It was a mega drive being conducted from multiple locations for people with 2 to 11 months of experience. There were two rounds: Amcat based aptitude test followed by the technical + HR (both elimination). I was able to clear them all.</p>

<p>A few days later they confirmed my onboarding over a mail and asked to fill up the EAF form. After another few days, I was asked to upload my academic and other documents. Their portal started showing my status as pending for offer letter.</p>

<p>I waited for few weeks and when there were no further updates I wrote to them asking for the same. They replied me saying that there was no open demand matching my profile at that time and requested me to wait for some more days.</p>

<p>This whole process took 3-4 months but there was no response yet. I wrote to them again and asked whether they will send me the offer or not? They replied that they have archived my profile as per their policy and I need to reapply again. Slow Claps!</p>

<p>These same events happened to my another friend who attended this from a different location and many others whom I also know.</p>

<p>However, wasting our time must not have been their aim. So, why did they do this?</p>

<p>Was this done to get some new project showing a “virtual resource pool”, this is what I concluded.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
