<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>getdilip.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
   <description>A page to express thoughts, share ideas and finally a transformation from Agyani to A Gyani!</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Buddhi and Gyani</title>
	  <link>//buddhi-and-gyani</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-26T15:48:00+05:30</pubDate>
	  <guid>//buddhi-and-gyani</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote>
  <p>A similar type of story was narrated to me by a teacher of mine on the account of me acting an over-smart: Henceforth this &gt;story has been a torchbearer calming me and showing me my height periodically.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>In my words it goes like this:</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Manohar and Sujata had twin kids named Buddhi and Gyani, both were five years old. On their fifth birthday celebration, Manohar discovered that his son Buddhi could dance. They appreciated his talent and motivated him to do better.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Gyani was asked to concentrate on studies as he was believed to be an ordinary boy from the crowd.</p>

<p>One day Manohar’s friend Rishi with his wife visited his home. As of conventional tradition, the parents wished to showcase how smart their son was, they asked Buddhi to perform a dance. Bravo! It was a wonderful dance they all applauded with an ovation. Gyani was left unnoticed again.</p>

<p>Rishi suggested Manohar make Buddhi join a dance academy which would allow him to excel in his talent. This was a good idea, Next day Manahor took Buddhi to a renowned dance Academy;</p>

<p>He also took Gyani thinking if he too could learn a little, thus both the child got their admission.</p>

<p>A month later Manohar visited his son’s dance teacher to get the feedback. He was shocked on hearing his son’s report card. Gyani once unnoticed and assumed inferior was the best student at the Academy and Buddhi was miles behind!</p>

<p><strong>“Judge People on their Potential rather their outer appearance. The first benchers are often found lagging behind in Practical Life, and a Backbencher when mentored does better”</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
